Francesco Dondi

The guarantee of experience, the enthusiasm for good engineering.

Latest version of this CV at: github.com/Fdondi/cv-latex/blob/main/cv_en.pdf Zugerstarsse 66, 8810 Horgen, ZH \Box +41 76 456 50 32 ☑ francesco314@gmail.com in francesco-dondi ♠ Fdondi

> Born 29/10/1990 Italian citizen, C permit Married, no children



00000

0000

00000

Who I am

As a seasoned software developer, I bring a wealth of experience in developing robust software solutions, optimizing SQL databases, and implementing effective data analytics. My expertise ranges from securing and improving server configurations to developing endto-end sophisticated software solutions. I'm known among my peers and supervisors for being a reliable, intelligent, and friendly colleague, one who is always ready to take on responsibility and contribute to the team's success.

Professional Experience

DoubleCloud

Company size: 50-100

Firebolt

Company size: 50-100

10/2017 - 05/2020 **Software Developer**, Zürich

Company size: 100.000

Ascent Software Company size: 50-100

04/2015 - 04/2016 Rulex Inc. /CNR

Company size: 5

03/2023 - 09/2023 **Software Developer**, Zürich

Maintained and developed the infrastructure around managed Click-House, in particular:

- Secured metrics server by adding Nginx
- Improved SaltStack configuration
- Solved bugs in Telegraf Go plugins

06/2021 - 09/2022 **Software Developer**, Zürich

Maintained and developed the SQL optimization engine and testing infrastructure.

- Expanded supported SQL syntax and optimizations
- o reworked the test framework to support new test suite
- o contributed to rewriting to higher standards the optimization engine

08/2020 - 02/2021 **Developer / Analyst**, Zug

F-Trust O Maintained and developed a Trading Engine (C++)

- Company size: 5 o redesigned, implemented and migrated storage (PostgreSQL)
 - o extracted and integrated data from multiple log streams
 - analyzed data to highlight opportunities for improvement (Julia)

Google Within Search, productionized an initially experimental tool (C++).

- Improved runtime from days to hours
- added support for new kinds of data
- o made the results easily visualizable and monitorable
- o made onboarding orders of magnitude faster for most cases

04/2016 - 10/2017 Software Developer, Luqa, Malta

I helped maintain and develop a driver (C++) for automotive communications, running both on regular computers and embedded (QNX real-time OS) systems.

Junior Developer, Genua, Italy

Explored options for speeding up C algorithms with CPU (OpenMP) and GPU (Nvidia CUDA) parallelization. Transported MATLAB algorithms to Python.

Skills

Programming

C++

- C++/Abseil

- C++/Boost

Java SQL

Clickhouse SQL

- PostgreSQL

Python

Julia

Go

Tools

BASH

Linux

Windows

Visual Studio

AWS storage

Docker

Git

Jenkins CI

SSH

VIM

Valgrind

Flamegraph

Kafka

gRPC

Nvidia CUDA

OpenMP Competences

Testing Debugging

DevOps

Design Docs

Embedded Dev.

Agile Dev.

Languages

English Italiano

Deutsch Français



Formal education

2023 H1	Business Analytics: From Data to Decisions, Imperial College Business School			
2009–2015	Galileian School of Higher Education , <i>University of Padua</i> , University-level enriching program for gifted students, $98/100$			
2012-2014	Master Degree in Mathematics, University of Padua, 108/110			
2009–2012	Bachelor Degree in Mathematics, University of Padua, 110/110 cum Laude			
2004-2009	High School - Science Track, added IT, French, Liceo Fermi, Bologna, 100/100 cum Laude			

Continuous Learning

Data Science/Analytics

Nov 2023	Linkedin	Data Fluency: Exploring and Describing Data	Data Analysis	
Nov 2023	Linkedin	Power BI Essential Training	Data Visualization	
Oct 2023	Linkedin	Business Intelligence for Consultants	Probability	
Oct 2023	Linkedin	Data Analytics for Business Professionals	Microsoft Power BI	
Oct 2023	Linkedin	Excel: Economic Analysis and Data Analytics	Microsoft Excel	00000
Oct 2023	Linkedin	The Non-Technical Skills of Effective Data Scientists	Pandas	
		Machine Learning/LLMs/AI		
Jan 2024	Coursera	Generative AI with Large Language Models	LLMs	
		Programming languages		
Nov 2023	Linkedin	C# Essential Training 1: Types and Control Flow	C#	
Oct 2023	Linkedin	Learning MATLAB	MATLAB	
		Embedded development		
Nov 2023	Linkedin	C Programming for Embedded Applications	C Embedded	
		Cloud and DevOps		
Feb 2023	Linkedin	AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (SAA-C02)	Cloud Admin	••••
		Cert Prep: 1 Cloud Services Overview	AWS Cloud	
Jan 2023	Linkedin	DevOps Foundations: Going Cloud Native	DevOps	

Projects

Embedded



BTC Arduino monitor

github.com/Fdondi/arduino-btc

A bot checking Bitcoin prices and blinking a green led if the price is above average, red if below. The speed of blinking depends on the magnitude of the change.

LLMs / Prompt engineering



Dec 2023 Deutsches Wörterbuch

chat. openai. com/g/g-bpvvdz IKE-deutsches-worter buch

A CustomGPT, takes one word and provides grammar, explanation in German and English, examples of use, and a final image visualizing the concept. Clarifies ambiguous or misspelled words, can discuss any user doubt. Can adjust German level used both automatically and on request.

Personal

Hobbies: Reading, hiking, biking, swimming.

Nov 2023

C++ Embedded

Arduino